# Siva Sankar. B

# Assistant Manager - Industrial Automation

Address Coimbatore, TN, 641111

**Phone** 770 8091377

E-mail sivasan002@gmail.com

Proactive Automation Expert having in-depth knowledge of various programming languages and best practices for development. Solutions-based collaborator well-versed in testing and simulating automated machinery, developing and implementing automated testing methodologies and supervising testing activities. Offering 14+ years of experience developing and applying technology to monitor and control production and delivery of Product and Service.

### Skills

- > Process automation
- Project management
- PLC/Motion Controller Programming
- Protocol Handled CANOpen, Profibus, Modbus, Modbus TCP/IP and Profinet
- HMI/SCADA Development & Report Development
- > Eplan Document preparation
- VFD and Servo Drives Programming
- Languages C, VB 6.0, SQL 2005, ASP.Net Basics

# **Work History**

# 2016-10 -

Current

### Assistant Manager - Automation (R&D).

Elgi Ultra Limited, Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu

- Complete owner for Electrical electronics and automation of new product development R&D.
- Established Pick and place robot for the textile industry which is having PLC and 11 servo drives are configured under CANopen Protocol. Machine Powered by advanced 50AH LiFePO4 battery pack which is communicated over RS485 Protocol.
- General roles are Product selection, Price Negotiation, Concept development, Software development and product validation against deliverable commitments.
- Expert programming of PLC, HMI and Servo drives. Communication debugging using PCAN analyzer.
- Preparation of Electrical wiring and user manual.

- Conducting Training Program to internal and external teams
- Test jig programming for pre-assemblies load test validation.
- Attended Daily meetings with quality assurance, developers and project managers to assess scope and timeline of project.
- Product installation and validation at customer place to ensure and optimize the machine operation.
- Kept on track with deadlines for development cycle times.
- Continuous Software and Hardware Improvement Based On the Feedback From Service Team & End User.
- Managing team of 6 members to produce quality panel wiring, machine integration, inspection and testing.
- Customer requirement study and supporting to marketing and production team.

## 2007-11 - 2016- Technical Lead – Application Development.

Innovative Contrrols, Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu

- **Application Study** Customer Requirement Study and deciding suitable automation solution.
- Architecture Planning Selection of suitable products like PLC, HMI/SCADA,
   Drives and building planning communication and interconnection network.
- Panel Design and Documentation developing documentation using EPLAN software and supporting production and sales team. User manual preparation. Preparation of I/O List, Cable termination, JB Details, Panel Wiring Interconnections.
- Application Development in house development of PLC logics including critical PID loop, HMI/SCADA development, VFD parameters listing, Motion controller programming, single/multi axis servo drive programming. Experienced with various programming languages – LAD, ST and FBD.
- Control Panel Inspection & Testing Responsible Panel wiring inspection,
   Conducting Acceptance Tests, and documentation.
- Installation and commissioning Installation of control panel at customer
  place and carrying interconnections as per the planned document.
  Loading the application and validating the machine operation against the
  requirement. Guiding supervisors for cable Laying, Panel Wiring and
  earthing Termination.
- Team Management Handling team for application development, conducting necessary training and tools. Conducting regular meeting to track project timeline and provide required support.
- **Customer Training** conducted training for machine operation and troubleshooting.
- Troubleshooting & Service On demand customer service and application improvements.

09

- Power Analysis Study Conducting power analysis test and providing harmonics study and recommendation reports. Suggesting suitable APFC panel to sales Team.
- SCADA/Historian, EMS Having experience of SCADA and reporting for various applications using Schneider electric Vijeo Citect, PME8.2. used SQL/Access database for data management.
- Various Platforms worked Application developed for various verticals
   Packaging, food, beverage, textile, steel, water treatment, furnace, cutting and finishing etc.

### **Key Projects List**

- Arc Furnace Automation at Saint Gobain SEFPRO, Palakad.
- Arc Furnace Automation CUMI, Kochin.
- PEMA Panel Welding Line Automation BHEL, Trichy.
- Cake Plant Automation Britannia industries, Uttaranchal.
- Extruder line complete automation El Dupont India, Madurai.
- Micro Grit Plant automation CUMI, Korraty.
- Tata project Elgi compressor line automation, kota thermal power plant, Rajasthan.
- Energy Management System (Ems), Brm Line-3 Automation In JSW Steels, Mecheri.
- Gearbox testing system at ZF Wind Energy, Coimbatore.
- Substation automation in Saint Gobain, palakkad.
- Energy monitoring system and reports ITC Coimbatore, united breweries Itd. Palakkad.
- HVAC Control system support to CRI Coimbatore.
- Sewage treatment plant automation in TWICL, Tirupur.
- Flow Wrap packaging machine automation BELLA, Dindigul.
- Board Filling Machine, Color pencils packing machines Automation –
   Umesh pencils, pollachi.
- Moulding machine automation support to Sarvamangala Engineers,
   Coimbatore,
- Copy bite candy wrap machine automation in Lotte india, Cuddalore.
- Gang-saw marble cutting machine automation Madav marbles, salem,

#### Data Engineer – Content Development 2006-06 - 2007-08

ALTIUS CONTENT SOLUTIONS (P) LIMITED, Coimbatore, Tamil Nadu

Job Responsibilities Include Focuses On Developing Parametric Engineering E-Content For The Verticals Of MRO (Maintenance Repair And Overhauls), Electronics And Semiconductors, Textile, Polymers, Environmental Engineering And Consumer Durables And Non Durables. Company Presently Engaged In Developing Large Volume Parametric Content Of Electrical And Electronics Components (Digital And Analog) For Two Of The world Largest E-Commerce Companies.

### Education

#### B.E: Electrical, Electronics Engineering Technologies 2002-06 - 2006-04

PSNA College of Engineering And Technology. - Dindigul

Graduated with 73% GPA

10th Std. 1999-06 - 2000-05

Government High School - Bommiampatti, Salem

• Completed with 80.2%

12th Std. 2000-06 - 2001-05

> Government Hr.Sec.School - Nadupatti, Salem Completed With 83.35%

### Softwares

Schneider - Unity pro XL, Somachine, Vijeo Designer, Vijeo Designer Lite, Vijeo Citect, PME8.2, ZellioSoft, TwidoSoft, Concept. Excellent Siemens - Microwin, Tia Portal 14, Simatic Manager Step 7. Very Good Horner - Cscape Excellent 

Good

Very Good

Very Good

Very Good

Mitsubishi - GX Works3

Codesys software Parker - PDQ Software

Microsoft office, Microsoft Projects

### **Personal Information**

Father Name: Baby Naidu. R

Date Of Birth: June 07, 1984.

Married

Gender : Male

Marital Status:

Nationality: Indian

# Languages

English

Tamil

Telungu

Excellent

Excellent

Good

# **Declaration**

I herewith declare that the above-furnished particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief. I also declare that I will work to the best of my ability, if I get this job.

Place: Thanks & Regards,

**Date:** (Siva Sankar. B)